<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic</title>
    <link>http://pieterbonte.be/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://pieterbonte.be/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Academic</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://pieterbonte.be/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Academic</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/talk/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/talk/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Wowchemy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further event details, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page elements&lt;/a&gt; such as image galleries, can be added to the body of this page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;LDESTS: Enabling efficient storage and querying of large volumes of time series data on Solid pods</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/01-hfrr-194-tm-7-b-2-n-4-d-5-rnj-8-r-8-mj/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/01-hfrr-194-tm-7-b-2-n-4-d-5-rnj-8-r-8-mj/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context-aware query derivation for IoT data streams with DIVIDE enabling privacy by design</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/01-h-2-wjkqbsev-37-d-3-azdgpsz-0-n-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/01-h-2-wjkqbsev-37-d-3-azdgpsz-0-n-6/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>POD-QUERY: Schema Mapping and Query Rewriting for Solid Pods</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/01-hfxxcedy-864-sva-6-vrarwq-64-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/01-hfxxcedy-864-sva-6-vrarwq-64-d/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-time estimation and monitoring of COVID-19 aerosol transmission risk in office buildings</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/01-gx-2-yyjda-626-er-3-c-92-et-83-vme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/01-gx-2-yyjda-626-er-3-c-92-et-83-vme/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RoXi : a framework for reactive reasoning</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/01-h-3-m-1-dbbgmxg-1-hh-993-j-2-xkx-00/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/01-h-3-m-1-dbbgmxg-1-hh-993-j-2-xkx-00/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming linked data : a survey on life cycle compliance</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/01-h-25-d-7-r-52-eq-31-w-7-xy-4-g-9-qkm-2-d/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/01-h-25-d-7-r-52-eq-31-w-7-xy-4-g-9-qkm-2-d/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming linked data : from vision to practice</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/01-grtz-22-tc-199-h-4-va-0-haq-27-mw-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/01-grtz-22-tc-199-h-4-va-0-haq-27-mw-7/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards cascading reasoning for generic edge processing</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/01-h-3-m-18-xqqgegs-8-tst-8-fzy-15-m-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/01-h-3-m-18-xqqgegs-8-tst-8-fzy-15-m-7/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Linked Data: From Vision to Practice</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/post/streaminglinkeddata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 11:55:24 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/post/streaminglinkeddata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am excited to announce that together with Riccardo Tommasini, Fabiano Spiga, and Emanuele Della Valle, we wrote a book on Streaming Linked Data. The book provides a comprehensive overview of core concepts and technological foundations for continuous engineering of Web streams. It presents various systems and applications and includes real-world examples. Last not least, it introduces the readers to RSP4J, a novel open-source project that aims to gather community efforts in software engineering and empirical research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book starts with an introductory chapter that positions the work by explaining what motivates the design of specific techniques for processing data streams using Web technologies. Chapter 2 briefly summarizes the necessary background concepts and models needed to understand the remaining content of the book. Subsequently, chapter 3 focuses on processing RDF streams, taming data velocity in an open environment characterized by high data variety. It introduces query answering algorithms with RSP-QL and analytics functions over streaming data. Chapter 4 presents the life cycle of streaming linked data, it focuses on publishing streams on the Web as a prerequisite aspect to make data findable and accessible for applications. Chapter 5 touches on the problems of benchmarks and systems that analyze Web streams to foster technological progress. It surveys existing benchmarks and introduces guidelines that may support new practitioners in approaching the issue of continuous analytics. Finally, chapter 6 presents a list of examples and exercises that will help the reader to approach the area, get used to its practices and become confident in its technological possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, this book is mainly written for graduate students and researchers in Web and stream data management. It collects research results and will guide the next generation of researchers and practitioners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can (pre)order the book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Streaming-Linked-Data-Vision-Practice/dp/3031153707/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RoXi Reasoner</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/project/roxi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 11:33:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/project/roxi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RoXi provides a uniform framework for Reactive Reasoning applications including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incremental maintenance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RDF Stream Processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Temporal Reasoning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RoXi uses some of the internals of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/oxigraph/oxigraph&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;oxigraph&lt;/a&gt;, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://crates.io/crates/spargebra&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;sparqlalgebra&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://crates.io/crates/oxrdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;OxRDF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RoXi can be included as a library, run in server mode through CLI or in the browser using web assembly.
You can try it out in your &lt;a href=&#34;https://pbonte.github.io/roxi/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;own browser&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RoXi supports datalog reasoning using &lt;a href=&#34;https://w3c.github.io/N3/spec/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;N3&lt;/a&gt; syntax. The whole N3 spec is currently not supported yet, but this is work in progress. Currently we support rules with plain datalog expressivity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bridging the gap between expressivity and efficiency in stream reasoning : a structural caching approach for IoT streams</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8756504/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8756504/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical pattern matching for anomaly detection in time series</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8770497/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8770497/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OWL2Streams: an Evaluation Framework for Expressive Stream Reasoning </title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/project/owl2streams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 07:03:55 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/project/owl2streams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;need-for-expressive-stream-reasoning-benchmark&#34;&gt;Need for Expressive Stream Reasoning Benchmark&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various benchmarks exist to evaluate expressive reasoning over static data sources. On the other hand, a plethora of benchmarks exists to evaluate RDF Stream Processing with no or limited support for reasoning. (Support for RDFS reasoning at most.) However, no benchmarks are available to evaluate expressive reasoning over continuous data streams. Therefore, we introduce &lt;strong&gt;OWL2Streams&lt;/strong&gt;, an evaluation framework for expressive stream reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-expressive-reasoning&#34;&gt;Why Expressive Reasoning?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many domains rely on rich background knowledge to fully capture the domain, such as Pervasive Health or the Internet of Things (IoT), requiring Expressive Reasoning to fully capture their domain knowledge. Furthermore,  most IoT labeled ontologies on &lt;a href=&#34;https://lov.linkeddata.es/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Linked Open Vocabularies&lt;/a&gt;  require expressive reasoning techniques, such as OWL2 DL, to be fully interpreted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pushing-optimizations&#34;&gt;Pushing Optimizations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OWL2Streams aims at pushing optimizations for expressive reasoning over continuous data streams. It makes a distinction between static data, describing background information, and streaming data.
OWL2Streams pushes optimizations for the following challenges:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Size of the static data&lt;/em&gt;: the larger the size of the static data, the slower the reasoning. Optimizations can focus on only extracting relevant parts of the static data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Expressivity of the ontology&lt;/em&gt;: the expressivity negatively impacts the reasoning time, optimizations can focus on extracting only relevant statements from the ontology TBox.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frequency of the stream&lt;/em&gt;: the faster the updates in the stream, the faster the reasoning process needs to be able to provide results. Optimizations can focus on first filtering relevant facts from the data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Number of parallel streams&lt;/em&gt;: More streams imply more data, however, challenges arise when data from various streams need to be correlated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Numeric data streams&lt;/em&gt;: in domains such as the IoT, many streams contain numeric data. However,  data property reasoning is not supported by many OWL2 reasoners. Optimizations could focus on filtering out events with numeric values that are not useful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data Expiration&lt;/em&gt;: next to reasoning over the addition of data, the removal of data is even more complex. Optimizations could investigate adapted incremental reasoning techniques for expressive reasoning. (Currently, none exist for OWL2 DL.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;supported-scenarios&#34;&gt;Supported Scenarios&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, OWL2Streams supports three different scenarios focussing on different optimization opportunities. These scenarios are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Smart City&lt;/em&gt;: an adaption of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/CityBench/Benchmark&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;City Bench&lt;/a&gt; containing more elaborate background knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Smart Building&lt;/em&gt;:  a COVID-19 scenario, consisting of sensors that measure the air quality in various rooms. The domain knowledge allows to infer if certain rooms have higher probabilities for COVID-19 infections, based on the air quality and the activities in each room.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;University Management&lt;/em&gt;: An adaptation of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kracr/owl2bench&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;OWL2Bench benchmark&lt;/a&gt;.
This scenario consists of a university where students register and enroll in a certain program. The data stream consists of the enrollment of the students.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OWL2Streams is an evaluation framework for pushing the expressivity in Reasoning over continuous data streams. If you are interested, checkout out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/IBCNServices/OWL2Streams&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Github Repository&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;../../#contact&#34;&gt;contact&lt;/a&gt; me for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSP4J: An API for RSP</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/project/rsp4j/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 12:21:57 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/project/rsp4j/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;RSP4J is a library to build RDF Stream Processing (RSP) Engines according with the reference model RSP-QL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSP4J is inspired by the OWL API, and other works that aim at spreading the Semantic Web (Stream Reasoning) research by means of practical and usable software tools.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>StreamingMASSIF</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/project/streamingmassif/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 11:44:31 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/project/streamingmassif/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;StreamingMASSIF allows to perform cascading reasoning by combining various components. In its standard configuration it allows to filter meaningful events from a datastream through RDF Stream Processing, abstract the selection through DL reasoning and perform Complex Event Processing ontop of these abstraction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSP4J: An API for RDF Stream Processing</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/tommasini-2020-rsp-4-j/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/tommasini-2020-rsp-4-j/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards an Evaluation Framework for  Expressive Stream Reasoning</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/bonte-2021-towards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/bonte-2021-towards/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walk extraction strategies for node embeddings with RDF2Vec in knowledge graphs</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8724157/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8724157/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conditional constraints for knowledge graph embeddings</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8675058/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8675058/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context-aware route planning : a personalized and situation-aware multi-modal transport routing approach</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8681056/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8681056/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distributed continuous home care provisioning through personalized monitoring &amp; treatment planning</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8665815/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8665815/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RDF Stream processing prototyping with streaming MASSIF</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8681059/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8681059/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Anomaly Detection for Communication Networks: An Autoencoder Approach</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/bonte-2020-unsupervised/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/bonte-2020-unsupervised/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/slides/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/slides/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-slides-in-markdown-with-wowchemy&#34;&gt;Create slides in Markdown with Wowchemy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wowchemy&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://owchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js#pdf-export&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;porridge = &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;
if porridge == &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;:
    print(&amp;quot;Eating...&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = ;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
Three
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
- Only the speaker can read these notes
- Press `S` key to view
{{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/media/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt; slide background-image=&amp;quot;/media/boards.jpg&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide background-color=&amp;quot;#0000FF&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide class=&amp;quot;my-style&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34;&gt;.reveal section h1,
.reveal section h2,
.reveal section h3 {
  color: navy;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/discussions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C-Sprite : efficient hierarchical reasoning for rapid RDF stream processing</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8635009/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8635009/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIVIDE : adaptive context-aware query derivation for IoT data streams</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8665820/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8665820/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficiënte verwerking van heterogene IoT-data aan de hand van expressieve redeneertechnieken</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8612860/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8612860/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantics-based platform for context-aware and personalized robot interaction in the internet of robotic things</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8603541/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8603541/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subset reasoning for event-based systems</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8627930/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8627930/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards optimizing hospital patient transports by automatically identifying interpretable causes of delays</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8623325/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8623325/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A query model for ontology-based event processing over RDF streams</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8581984/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8581984/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context-aware patient monitoring through sensor streams</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8577848/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8577848/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SENSdesc : connect sensor queries and context</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8552458/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8552458/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharing health data in Belgium : a home care case study using the Vitalink platform</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8550825/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8550825/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming MASSIF : cascading reasoning for efficient processing of iot data streams</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8586329/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8586329/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards a cascading reasoning framework to support responsive ambient-intelligent healthcare interventions</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8581923/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8581923/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context-aware and self-learning dynamic transport scheduling in hospitals</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8541544/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8541544/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The MASSIF platform : a modular and semantic platform for the development of flexible IoT services</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8533438/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8533438/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The OCarePlatform : a context-aware system to support independent living</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8541182/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8541182/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards ontology based event processing</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8506060/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8506060/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generic semantic platform for the user-friendly development of intelligent IoT services</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8506056/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8506056/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving OWL RL reasoning in N3 by using specialized rules</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8503498/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8503498/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning semantic rules for intelligent transport scheduling in hospitals</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8505900/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8505900/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining semantic rules for optimizing transport assignments in hospitals</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8506052/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8506052/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic context consolidation and rule learning for optimized transport assignments in hospitals</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8500134/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8500134/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User-friendly and scalable platform for the design of intelligent IoT services : a smart office use case</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8506046/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/8506046/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation and optimized usage of OWL 2 reasoners in an event-based eHealth context</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/6990308/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/6990308/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event-driven rule-based reasoning using EYE</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/7033546/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/7033546/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ontology reasoning using rules in an eHealth context</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/7034224/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/7034224/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic intelligence for real-time automated media production</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/7237124/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/7237124/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards a social and context-aware multi-sensor fall detection and risk assessment platform</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/7235308/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/7235308/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OCareClouds: improving home care by interconnecting elderly, care networks and their living environments</title>
      <link>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/5660331/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://pieterbonte.be/publication/5660331/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
